<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Other">
    <name>Keyword Extractor</name>
    <shortDescription>Extracts relevant keywords from documents.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node analyses documents and extracts relevant keywords 
            using cooccurrence statistics as described in 
            "Keyword extraction from a single document using word co-occurrence
            statistical information" by Y.Matsuo and M. Ishizuka.
            <br />
            First, the most frequent terms (see node settings) are extracted and
            then clustered together using the Jensen-Shannon divergence and 
            Mutual Information measures. Once this is done, each term is ranked 
            in decreasing order of the deviation between their expected cluster 
            cooccurrence and the actual observed cooccurrence value. The terms 
            with the highest divergence are returned as keywords.
            <br />
            A term can be considered as member of a cluster if it is similar to 
            all the terms inside it according to at least one of the similarity 
            measures. If more than one cluster meets this condition, the 
            one with the highest average score will be used. If no cluster 
            is similar, a new one is created.
            <br /> 
            Setting the console's output level to DEBUG will make this node 
            display the contents of the clusters and also the similarity between
             terms.
        </intro>
        <option name="Number of keywords to extract">
             The number of keywords to extract per document.
        </option>
        <option name="Percentage of unique terms in the document to use for the 
        chi-square measures">
             The percentage of the set of unique terms in the document to use 
             for the term clusters.
             The article this node is based on provides 30% as a rule of thumb.
        </option>
        <option name="Ignore tags">
             If this option is checked, the node will only compare terms based 
             on their word content. In other words, tags and any other meta 
             information will be ignored.
             This will not affect the output documents, only the way they are 
             analysed.
        </option>
        <option name="Pointwise mutual information threshold">
            Terms whose pointwise mutual information score is greater than or 
            equal to this value will be considered as similar and thus clustered
             together.
            <br />
            This similarity measure typically ranges from 0 to infinity but has 
            been normalized from 0 to 1 using arctan(value)/(pi/2).
        </option>
        <option name="Normalized L1 norm threshold">
            Terms whose normalized L1 norm score is greater than or 
            equal to this value will be considered as similar and thus clustered
             together.
            <br />
            This similarity measure ranges from 0 to 1 inclusively.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
        
    <ports>
        <dataIn name="Documents input table" index="0">
        The input table which contains the documents to analyse.</dataIn>
        <dataOut name="Keywords output table" index="0">
        The output table which contains (keyword term, deviation value, 
        associated document) tuples.
        </dataOut>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
