<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	icon="../../../icons/TextProcDefault.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Unique Term Extractor</name>
    <shortDescription>Creates a global set of terms over all documents.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node creates a global set of terms over all documents. Optionally, it is possible to filter the top-k 
            words in terms of frequencies. There are three different frequencies to choose from for filtering: the term frequency,
            the document frequency and the inverse document frequency. <br/>
            <ul>
                <li>Term Frequency (<tt>TF</tt>): Overall count of a term in all documents. </li>
                <li>Document Frequency (<tt>DF</tt>): Number of documents in which a term occurs.</li>
				<li>Inverse Document Frequency (<tt>IDF</tt>): The logarithm of the total number of documents divided by the <tt>DF</tt>.</li>
            </ul>
            More information about term frequencies can be found <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tf%E2%80%93idf">here</a>.<br/>
            <br/>
        </intro>
        <option name="Document column">
            Select the document column to extract the terms from.
    	</option>
    	<option name="Most frequent terms (k)"> 
    		Check, if the data table should be restricted on the top k most frequent terms.
    	</option>
    	<option name="Filter terms by">
            If the 'Most frequent terms (k)' option is checked, the terms are sorted by the selected frequency method 
            (<tt>TF</tt>, <tt>DF</tt> or <tt>IDF</tt>). Only the top-k most frequent terms are then added to the data 
            table. 
    	</option>
    	<option name="Append index column">
            If checked, the node appends an index column containing a unique index for each term. This is especially useful
            for replacing words with numbers while preparing documents for deep learning.
    	</option>
    	 <option name="Append frequency columns">
            If checked, the node appends a term frequency (<tt>TF</tt>), document frequency (<tt>DF</tt>) and inverse document frequency (<tt>IDF</tt>) column.
    	</option>
    	<option name="Number of threads">
			The number of threads used to process the documents.
		</option>
    </fullDescription>
        
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Documents input table" index="0">The input table
        containing the documents.</inPort>    
        <outPort name="Terms output table" index="0">An output table
        containing a unique term column, frequency columns and an index column.</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>