<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TikaParser.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Tika Parser URL Input</name>
	<shortDescription>
		Tika Parser URL Input parses all kinds of file format
		supported by the Apache Tika library.
	</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node has the same function as the Tika Parser node, which
			is to parse any documents that are
			supported by Tika. The difference
			is that this node takes file paths from a string column as input. The
			type of the
			files can be selected in the
			configuration dialog. Users
			have the
			choice between selecting the
			file extensions, or the
			MIME-types. What
			kind of information that are to be extracted from the
			file
			(metadata
			and content) can also be selected in the dialog.
			If
			possible, user can
			also extract files that are embedded in the input
			files, such as
			attachments in E-mails, etc, and store them in a
			specified directory.
			Authentication setting is also provided to parse
			any encrypted files.
		</intro>
		<option name="File path column">
			The column containing the paths to files to
			parse.
		</option>
		<option name="Choose which type to parse">
			Specify how to choose the file types that are to
			be parsed. There are two
			options, either through the file extensions
			or the MIME-types.
		</option>
		<option name="File Extension">
			If selected, the list of all file extensions that
			are supported by Tika
			will be shown.
		</option>
		<option name="MIME-Type">
			If selected, the list of all MIME-types that are supported by Tika
			will be shown. For more information about MIME-types and their
			extensions, check
			<a href="http://www.freeformatter.com/mime-types-list.html">here</a>
			.
		</option>
		<option name="Metadata">
			The list of all available information that could be parsed from the
			files by Tika. For more details about the metadata, check
			<a
				href="https://tika.apache.org/1.13/api/org/apache/tika/metadata/TikaCoreProperties.html">here</a>
			.
		</option>
		<option name="Create error column">
			If checked, an additional error column will be created. This string column will contain any error messages that appear while parsing the files.
		</option>
		<option name="New error output column">
			The name of the new error column. 
		</option>
		<option name="Extract attachments and embedded files">
			If checked, any embedded files that are contained
			in the input files
			would be extracted and stored in the output
			directory.
		</option>
		<option name="Ouput directory">
			Specify the directory where the extracted files
			should be stored. If the specified directory doesn't exist, the node will try to create it.
		</option>
		<option name="Parse encrypted files">
			If checked, the node will try to open any detected
			encrypted files using the given password. If the password is invalid,
			a warning will be given.
		</option>
		<option name="Enter password">
			Specify the password for any encrypted files in
			the directory. Note: this password will be used to open all encrypted
			files in the directory.
		</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort name="Table containing the filepaths" index="0">
			The input
			table containing the URLs or paths to files that are to be parsed.
			The
			input table has to contain at least one String column.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Metadata output table" index="0">An output table
			containing the parsed document data. The columns are the same as what
			was selected in the Metadata list in the configure dialog.
		</outPort>
		<outPort name="Attachment output table" index="1">An output table
			containing the names of input files that contain any embedded files
			and also the paths to the extracted files in the output directory.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>