<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcEnrichment.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Stanford Tagger</name>
    <shortDescription>Assigns part of speech tags to terms. 
    Suitable for French, German, English and Spanish texts.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            <p>
            This node assigns to each term of a document a part of speech (POS)
            tag. It is applicable for French, English, German and Spanish texts. The 
            underlying tagger models are models of the Stanford NLP group:<br/>
            <a href="http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/tagger.shtml">http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/tagger.shtml</a> 
            </p>
            <p>
            For English texts the Penn Treebank tag set is used:<br/>
            <a href="http://www.cis.upenn.edu/~treebank">http://www.cis.upenn.edu/~treebank</a>).<br/>
            For German texts the STTS tag set is used:<br/>
            <a href="http://www.ims.uni-stuttgart.de/projekte/CQPDemos/Bundestag/help-tagset.html">http://www.ims.uni-stuttgart.de/projekte/CQPDemos/Bundestag/help-tagset.html</a>.<br/>
            For French texts the French Treebank tag set is used:
            <a href="http://www.llf.cnrs.fr/Gens/Abeille/French-Treebank-fr.php">http://www.llf.cnrs.fr/Gens/Abeille/French-Treebank-fr.php</a>.
            For Spanish texts the Ancora Treebank tag set is used:
            <a href="https://nlp.stanford.edu/software/spanish-faq.shtml#tagset">https://nlp.stanford.edu/software/spanish-faq.shtml#tagset</a>.
            </p>
            <p>
            <b>Note:</b> the provided tagger models vary in memory consumption and processing speed. Especially the 
            models English bidirectional, German hgc, and Germany dewac require a lot of memory. For the usage of these
            models it is recommended to run KNIME with at least 2GB of heap space. To increase the heap space, change
            the -Xmx setting in the knime.ini file. If KNIME is running with less than 1.5GB heap space it is 
            recommended to use English left3words, English left3words caseless, or German fast models for tagging of 
            english or german texts. 
            </p>
            <p>
            Descriptions of the models (taken from the website of the Stanford
            NLP group):
            <ul>
                <li>English bidirectional: Trained on WSJ sections 0-18 using a 
                    bidirectional architecture and including word shape and 
                    distributional similarity features.</li>
                <li>English left3words: Trained on WSJ sections 0-18 and extra parser 
                    training data using the left3words architecture and includes word 
                    shape and distributional similarity features.</li>
                <li>English left3words caseless: Trained on WSJ sections 0-18 and extra 
                    parser training data using the left3words architecture and includes 
                    word shape and distributional similarity features. Ignores case.</li>
             </ul>
             </p>
             <p>   
             To use following tagger models, the specific language pack has to be installed.
             (File -> Install KNIME Extensions...)
             </p>
             <p>   
             <ul>
                <li>German hgc: Trained on the first 80% of the Negra corpus, which uses
                    the STTS tagset.</li>
                <li>German dewac: This model uses features from the distributional 
                    similarity clusters built from the deWac web corpus.</li>
                <li>German Fast: Lacks distributional similarity features, but is 
                    several times faster than the other alternatives.</li>
                <li>French: Trained on the French treebank.</li>
                <li>Spanish: Trained on the Spanish Ancora tagset.</li>
                <li>Spanish distsim: Trained on the French Spanish ancora tagset.</li>
            </ul>
            </p>
        </intro>
		<tab name="General options">
        <option name="Document column">
            The column containing the documents to tag.
        </option>
        <option name="Replace documents">
            If checked, the documents will be replaced by the new tagged documents. Otherwise the tagged
            documents will be appended as new column. 
        </option>
        <option name="Append column">
            The name of the new appended column, containing the tagged documents.            
        </option>
        <option name="Word tokenizer">
            Select the tokenizer used for word tokenization. Go to <i>Preferences -> KNIME -> Textprocessing</i>
            to read the description for each tokenizer.
        </option>
		<option name="Number of maximal parallel tagging processes">
            Defines the maximal number of parallel threads that are used for tagging. Please note, that for each thread
            a tagging model will be loaded into memory. If this value is set to a number greater than 1, make sure that
            enough heap space is available, in order to be able to load the models. If you are not sure how much heap is 
            available for KNIME, leave the number to 1.
        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Tagger options">
        <option name="Tagger model">
            The tagger model to use.
        </option>
        </tab>         
    </fullDescription>
        
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Documents input table" index="0">The input table
        containing the documents to tag.</inPort>    
        <outPort name="Documents output table" index="0">An output table
        containing the tagged documents.</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>