<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcEnrichment.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>OpenNLP NE Tagger</name>
    <shortDescription>Assigs named entity tags, such as "PERSON" or "LOCATION".
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node recognizes named enities based on opennlp models version 
            1.6.0 and assigns the corresponding tags to them. The following 
            entities are recognized: Persons, Locations, Organizations, Money, 
            Date, and Time. For more details of the OpenNlp natural language 
            processing toolkit, see 
            https://opennlp.apache.org/docs/
        </intro>
        <tab name="General options">
        <option name="Document column">
            The column containing the documents to tag.
        </option>
        <option name="Replace documents">
            If checked, the documents will be replaced by the new tagged documents. Otherwise the tagged
            documents will be appended as new column. 
        </option>
        <option name="Append column">
            The name of the new appended column, containing the tagged documents.            
        </option>
        <option name="Word tokenizer">
            Select the tokenizer used for word tokenization. Go to <i>Preferences -> KNIME -> Textprocessing</i>
            to read the description for each tokenizer.
        </option>
		<option name="Number of maximal parallel tagging processes">
            Defines the maximal number of parallel threads that are used for tagging. Please note, that for each thread
            a tagging model will be loaded into memory. If this value is set to a number greater than 1, make sure that
            enough heap space is available, in order to be able to load the models. If you are not sure how much heap is 
            available for KNIME, leave the number to 1.
        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Tagger options">
        <option name="Set named entities unmodifiable">
            Sets recognized named entity terms unmodifiable.
        </option>
        <option name="OpenNlp model">
            Specifies the OpenNLP model to use. Each model is able to recognize
            a certain type of named entities.
        </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
        
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Documents input table" index="0">The input table
        containing the documents to tag.</inPort>    
        <outPort name="Documents output table" index="0">An output table
        containing the tagged documents.</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>