<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 1.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcDocumentView.png" type="Visualizer">
	<name>Tagcloud</name>
	<shortDescription>Creates a tag cloud</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro> 
		
		 <p>A tag cloud is a representation of words indicating the importance of the
         words by manipulating the visual properties.
         Here we use the distribution of font size, transparency and
        boldness of the font.</p>
        
        <p>The user can change the following view properties on the fly:
            <ol>
            <li>Minimal and maximal font size</li>
            <li>The distribution of the font size (linear, logarithm or exponential)</li>
            <li>The font name</li>
            <li>The amount of bold terms</li>
            <li>The transperency of the labels</li>
            <li>Zooming</li>
            </ol>
        </p>
        
        <h3>Color of term:</h3>
        <p> To improve the variety of the tag cloud the colors of the terms are
        arranged. There are two possibilities.
        The user can create its own distribution method by adding a color 
        to the rows, using the color appender.</p>
        <p>
        If there were no colors added to the rows, the color will be arranged 
        using the type of the first term. The so preselected colors can afterwards 
        be changed on the fly.
        </p>
        
	
	<h3>HiLiting:</h3>
        <p> The terms may be selected by dragging
        a rectangle with the mouse over the points or 
        by clicking on points.
        The selected terms may be 
        hilited by either right-click to get the context menu or via the hilite
        menu in the menu bar.</p>
        <p> Important: If a term was found in more than one row, hiliting this term
        will cause all rows to be hilited, which contains this term.
        On the other hand, for hiliting a term it is sufficient that one of its
        representing rows was hilited.</p>
        
        </intro>
        
          <option name="Display all rows">
            If selected the histogram view displays all rows of the incoming data.
    </option>
    <option name="No. of rows to display">
            Defines the number of rows to be displayed in the histogram.
            This option is disabled if the 'Display all rows' option is selected.
    </option>
    <option name="Term column">
            The text of the terms in this column will be shown in the tagcloud.
            If the rows don't contain colors, the tag of the term is used for 
            determine the term color.
    </option>
    <option name="Value column">
            This value represents the importance of the term. Be aware that, the higher
            this value, the more important the term will be considered in the view.
            The value is used for the font size, the intensity of the font color 
            and the boldness of the font.
    </option>
    <option name="Ignore tags">
            If selected the tags are ignored. So two terms are equal, when 
            their words are equal. 
            For the color distribution will then always the first tag
            which was associated with the words be used.
            The new value of the term will be the sum over all terms, which 
            contain the same words.             
    </option>
    <option name="Kind of tagcloud">
            The view offers four kinds of tag cloud. 
            The look of the first three of them is the same, just the sorting 
            is different.
            <ol>
            <li>Simple table : The terms are shown in a table. The terms will be 
            sorted  in the order of their first appearance in the data table.</li>
            <li>Alphabetic table : The terms are shown in a table. The terms will be 
            sorted  in alphabetical order.</li>
            <li>Size-sorted table : The terms are shown in a table. The terms will be 
            sorted  in descending order of their values.</li>
            <li>Inside-Out tagcloud : In this view the terms are arranged
            in a kind of circular way. The goal is to display the most
            important terms in the middle and the others around. With
            this positioning the amount of white space is reduced and the important
            words gain a lot of attention. </li>
            </ol>
    </option>
        
        
	</fullDescription>
	<ports>
        <inPort name="Terms and values input table" index="0">
        The input table must contain at least one column with terms and 
        one column with a value.</inPort>
    </ports>    
  
    
    <views>
        <view index="0" name="Tagcloud">
                Displays the terms in a table tagcloud view. 
        </view>
    </views>    
	
</knimeNode>
