<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcDefault.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Tag Filter</name>
    <shortDescription>Filters document terms with certain tags assigned.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Filters terms contained in the input documents that have specific tags assigned.
            A term if not filtered out if at least one of it assigned tags is part of the specified tags. 
            If strict filtering is set, all assigned tags of a term have to be specified tags.
        </intro>

        <tab name="Tag filter options">
        <option name="Strict filtering">
             If strict filtering is checked, terms need to have all specified
             tags assigned. If  not checked, at least one assigned tag has to be part of the specified tags.
        </option>
        <option name="Filter matching">
             If checked, terms that have the specified tags assigned are filtered out,
             otherwise they are not filtered. If strict filtering is checked, all tags
             must match to filter or not a term.
        </option>
        <option name="Tag type">
             The type of the tags to filter.
        </option>
        <option name="Tags">
             The tags to filter for.
        </option>
        </tab>

        <tab name="Preprocessing options">
        <option name="Document column">
            The column containing the documents to preprocess.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Replace documents">
            If checked, the documents will be replaced by the new preprocessed documents. Otherwise the preprocessed
            documents will be appended as new column. 
        </option>

        <option name="Append column">
            The name of the new appended column, containing the preprocessed documents.            
        </option>
        
        <option name="Ignore unmodifiable tag">
              If checked, unmodifiable terms will be preprocessed too.
        </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort name="Documents to preprocess" index="0">
            The input table which contains the documents to preprocess.
        </inPort>
        <outPort name="Preprocessed documents." index="0">
            The output table which contains the preprocessed documents.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>