<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcDefault.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Zemberek Stemmer</name>
    <shortDescription>Disambiguates document terms and stems them afterwards.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	Stems terms contained in the input documents with the Zemberek stemming algorithm, terms will be 
        	disambiguated and reduced to their stem. The Zemberek stemming algorithm works for Turkish texts only.
        	
        	<br/><i>Warning:</i> It is highly recommended to use this node only with documents that have been tokenized with
        	the <i>Zemberek TurkishTokenizer</i>. Otherwise term information (letter case, tags etc.) might be lost. 
        	Please double-check the node configurations of the preceding nodes. 
		</intro>

        <tab name="Preprocessing options">
        <option name="Document column">
            The column containing the documents to preprocess.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Replace documents">
            If checked, the documents will be replaced by the new preprocessed documents. Otherwise the preprocessed
            documents will be appended as new column. 
        </option>

        <option name="Append column">
            The name of the new appended column, containing the preprocessed documents.            
        </option>
        
        <option name="Ignore unmodifiable tag">
              If checked, unmodifiable terms will be preprocessed too.
        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Stemming options">
        <option name="Maintain letter case">
        	If checked, the case of the letters of the stem will be preserved accordingly to their original term.
        </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort name="Documents to preprocess" index="0">
            The input table which contains the documents to preprocess.
        </inPort>
        <outPort name="Preprocessed documents." index="0">
            The output table which contains the preprocessed documents.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>