<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./learn.png" type="Learner" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Word2Vec Learner</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Train a Word2Vec model using documents.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node trains a Word2Vec model on unlabelled documents. The model will
        only learn word representations (vector for each word), that can be extracted
        using the Vocabulary Extractor Node.
        For more information on Word Vectors in general see:
        <a href="http://deeplearning4j.org/word2vec">http://deeplearning4j.org/word2vec</a>
        </intro>
     
    <tab name="Data Options">   
        <option name="Document Column">Column containing the Document or String to train on.</option>
    </tab>     
    <tab name="Learning Options">                
        <option name="Learning Rate">The starting learning rate.</option>
        <option name="Minimum Learning Rate">The minimum learning rate threshold. The learning rate will decay automatically over time.</option>
        <option name="Layer Size">The length of the resulting word vectors.</option>
        <option name="Batch Size">The number of words to use for each batch.</option>       
        <option name="Seed">A seed value to use for training.</option>       
        <option name="Number of Epochs">The number of epochs to train.</option>       
        <option name="Number of Training Iterations">The number of updates done for each batch.</option>    
        <option name="Context Window Size">Size of the context, meaning a window around each word to consider for learning.</option>        
        <option name="Minimum Word Frequency">Minimum frequency of a word to appear in the corpus to be considered for learning. Words
        with a lower frequency will not appear in the vocabulary contained in the Word Vector Model.</option>
        <option name="Sampling Rate">Threshold for configuring which higher-frequency words are randomly downsampled;
    	a useful range is (0, 1e-5).</option> 
        <option name="Use Hierarchical Softmax?">Whether to use hierarchical softmax. If checked negative sampling will be disabled.</option>               
        <option name="Negative Sampling Rate">The number of “noise words” that should be drawn.</option>
       	<option name="Elements Learning Algorithm">The <a href="https://arxiv.org/pdf/1411.2738.pdf">algorithm</a> to use to learn 
       	word representations.</option>  	
        <option name="Skip missing cells?">Whether rows containing missing cells should be skipped or not. If missing cells should not
        be skipped but the table contains missing cells the node will fail.</option>
    </tab>     
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Data Table">Table containing Document or String column.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Word Vector Model">Trained Doc2Vec Model.</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
