<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../../icons/TextProcDoc2String.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>StanfordNLP Relation Extractor</name>
    <shortDescription>Extracts relation triplets from documents.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
			Extracts relations triplets contained in sentences of a document by investigating relations of tagged named-entities.
			The node needs part-of-speech and named-entity tagged documents. 
			Additionally, there has to be a second document column containing lemmatized documents, which consist of terms converted to their canonical, dictionary or citation form.<br/>
			<br/>
			However, this node can also be used with plain documents by using the <i>Apply preprocessing</i> option.
			If this option is selected, part-of-speech tagging, named-entity tagging and lemmatizing will be done 
			by this node. The Stanford CoreNLP default settings are used in this case. Creating the same pipeline by using KNIME's Stanford nodes with default settings 
			will not necessarily lead to the same results as using the <i>Apply preprocessing</i> option, since KNIME is using the Penn-Treebank (PTB) tag set. This tag set uses the <tt>SYM</tt> tag for
			any kind of punctuation and quotation marks. However, Stanford CoreNLP uses a modified version of the PTB tag set to distinguish these symbols, since they are important for dependency parsing and natural logic annotation.<br/>
			<br/>
			The node creates four new columns: two object columns containing named-entities, one column containing the type of relation with the highest confidence and 
			a column containing the confidence for this relation. The node handles classic named-entities like <tt>PERSON</tt>, <tt>LOCATION</tt> and
			<tt>ORGANIZATION</tt>.<br/>
			Relation types that can be extracted are <tt>Live_In</tt>, <tt>OrgBased_In</tt>, <tt>Located_In</tt>, <tt>Work_For</tt> 
			and <tt>_NR</tt>. <br/> <tt>_NR</tt> specifies no relation between two entities. A detailed explanation of StanfordNLP's approach for relation extraction can be found in <a href="https://nlp.stanford.edu/pubs/relms2011.pdf">this article</a>.<br/>
			<br/>
			<i>Note</i>: Relation Extraction is a computationally expensive operation. For the usage of this
            node it is recommended to run KNIME with at least 2GB of heap space. To increase the heap space, change
            the -Xmx setting in the knime.ini file.<br/>
			<br/>      
            This node is based on Stanford CoreNLP 3.9.1.<br/>
            For more information about StanfordNLP and Relation Extraction, click <a href="https://stanfordnlp.github.io/CoreNLP/relation.html">here</a>.
		</intro>
		<option name="Document column">The document column to use.<br/> <i>Note</i>: If the <i>Apply preprocessing</i>
		option is unchecked, the documents have to be tagged by a part-of-speech tagger and a named-entity tagger (optionally). </option>
		<option name="Lemmatized document column">The document column containing the lemmatized documents.</option>
		<option name="Apply preprocessing">If checked, part-of-speech tagging, named-entity tagging and lemmatizing will be done by this node.</option>
		<option name="Number of threads">The number of threads to use.</option>
	</fullDescription>
		
	<ports>
        <inPort name="Documents input table" index="0">
        The input table which contains the documents and lemmatized documents (if needed).</inPort>
        <outPort name="Documents and extracted relation." index="0">
        The output table which contains data from the input table, extracted relations and a relation confidence.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>