<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode type="Learner" icon="../../../icons/TextProcDefault.png">
    <name>Topic Extractor (Parallel LDA)</name>

    <shortDescription>
        Simple parallel threaded implementation of LDA for topic detection.
    </shortDescription>

    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Simple parallel threaded implementation of 
            <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Latent_Dirichlet_allocation">LDA</a>, 
            following Newman, Asuncion, Smyth and Welling, 
            <a href="http://machinelearning.wustl.edu/mlpapers/paper_files/jmlr10_newman09a.pdf">
            Distributed Algorithms for Topic Models JMLR (2009), with SparseLDA sampling scheme and data structure</a> 
            from Yao, Mimno and McCallum, <a href="http://www.cs.umass.edu/~lmyao/papers/fast-topic-model10.pdf">
            Efficient Methods for Topic Model Inference on Streaming Document Collections,</a> KDD (2009).
            <p>
            The node uses the <a href="http://mallet.cs.umass.edu/">"MALLET: A Machine Learning for Language Toolkit."</a> 
            topic modeling library.
            <b>Note:</b> The current version of MALLET contains a known multi-threading bug that can cause the node to fail with an ArrayIndexOutOfBoundsException.
            Should you encounter this issue, setting the number of threads to one should solve the problem.
            </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Document column">
            The column that contains the pre-processed document.
        </option>
        <option name="Seed">
            The seed used for random number drawing.
        </option>
        <option name="No of topics">
            The number of topics to detect.
        </option>
        <option name="No of words per topic">
            The number of top words to extract per topic.
        </option>
        <option name="No of iterations">
            Number of iterations to perform (influences the runtime of the algorithm).
        </option>
        <option name="Alpha">
            The alpha parameter defines the Dirichlet prior on the per-document topic distributions.
            It defines the prior weight of topic k in a document. The library uses the given alpha for all topics. 
            Normally a number less than 1, e.g. 0.1, to prefer sparse topic distributions, 
            i.e. few topics per document.
        </option>
        <option name="Beta">
            The beta parameter defines the prior on per-topic multinomial distribution over words.
            It defines the prior weight of word w in a topic. The library uses the given beta for all words.
            Normally a number much less than 1, e.g. 0.001, to strongly prefer sparse word distributions, 
            i.e. few words per topic.
        </option>
        <option name="No of threads">
            Divides the input document collection into the specified number of threads and merges the 
            calculated statistics afterwards.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Document table">
            Data table with the document collection to analyze. Each row contains one document.
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Document table with topics">
            The document collection with topic assignments and the probability for each document to belong to a
            certain topic
        </outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Topic terms">
            The topic models with the terms and their weight per topic 
        </outPort>
        <outPort index="2" name="Iteration statistics">
            Table with statistics for each iteration 
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>