<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../icons/TextProcFrequencies.png" type="Learner">
    <name>Term co-occurrence counter</name>
    <shortDescription>
        Counts the number of co-occurrences for the given list of terms 
        within the different parts e.g. sentence, paragraph, section and title
        of the corresponding document.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            The node counts the number of co-occurrences for the given list of 
            terms within the selected parts e.g. sentence, paragraph, section and
             title of the corresponding document.
            The order two terms occur is not considered. Thus the occurrence
            of T1 followed by T2 is equal to the occurrence of T2 followed 
            by T1. The output table returns the term pairs in alphabetical 
            order.
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Document column">
            The column that contains the document to search for the 
            term co-occurrences.
        </option>
        <option name="Term column">
       		The column that contains the terms to compute the co-occurrence for.
		 </option>
		 <option name="Co-occurrence level">
		   Select the co-occurrence level to be calculated. 
		   They are ordered from more general (document co-occurrence)
		   to more specific (neighbors). The more general levels include
		   the more specific levels e.g. the sentence level includes the 
		   neighbor and title co-occurrence calculation.
		   Notice: The calculation of the more general statistic especially 
		   the document level statistics might result in a very large data 
		   table.
		 </option>
         <option name="Check term tags">
            The tags e.g. POS tags of a term are considered when matching terms
            if this option is selected. If this option is not selected only 
            their textual representation is checked when matching terms.
         </option>
		 <option name="Sort input table">
            Unselect this option if the input table is already sorted by the
            document column.
         </option>
         <option name="Maximum number of parallel proceses">
            Decrease the number of parallel processes in case of memory problems.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table">
            Input table with a document and term column
        </inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Co-occurrence table">
            Table with the co-occurrence statistics for the input table 
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
