<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcSource.png" type="Other">
    <name>RSS Feed Reader</name>
    <shortDescription>The RSS Feed Reader Node parses RSS/Atom feeds.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node parses feeds from the URLs specified in the input data table and retrieves information like title,
            description, publication date and article link from the feed entries. It is also possible to create a 
            document, XML and/or HTTP response code column. The document will be created from the feed entry information
            and the XML column shows the XML snippet for the specific feed entry.
             
            The RSS Feed Parser uses the <a href="https://rometools.github.io/rome/ROMEReleases/index.html">ROME(1.0)</a> library. 
            ROME supports following formats and versions:
            <ul>
                <li>RSS 2.0</li>
                <li>RSS 1.0</li>
                <li>RSS 0.94</li>
                <li>RSS 0.93</li>
                <li>RSS 0.92</li>
                <li>RSS 0.91 Userland</li>
                <li>RSS 0.91 Netscape</li>
                <li>RSS 0.90</li>
                <li>Atom 1.0</li>
                <li>Atom 0.3</li>
            </ul>
            For more information about <a href="https://rometools.github.io/rome/index.html">ROME</a>, visit their website.
        </intro>
        <option name="URL column">
            The URLs to get the feeds from.
        </option>
        <option name="Number of threads">
            Select the maximum number of threads that should be used to read the feeds.
        </option>
        <option name="Timeout">
            Set the timeout (in milliseconds) for connecting to and reading from the input source.
        </option>
        <option name="Create document column">
            If checked, the node creates an additional document column for each feed entry.
        </option>
        <option name="Create XML column">
            If checked, the node creates an additional XML column, containing the XML snippet for each feed entry.
        </option>
        <option name="Create HTTP status code column">
            If checked, the node create an additional integer column, containing the HTTP status code for each URL. This
            is only applicable for HTTP URLs.
        </option>
        <option name="Word tokenizer">
            Select the tokenizer used for word tokenization. Go to <i>Preferences -> KNIME -> Textprocessing</i>
            to read the description for each tokenizer.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>      
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Input table" index="0">
            An input table which contains a string column with URLs to RSS or Atom feeds.
        </inPort>
        <outPort name="Output table" index="0">
            An output table which contains parsed feed information.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>