<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcSource.png" type="Other">
    <name>RSS Feed Reader</name>
    <shortDescription>The RSS Feed Reader Node parses RSS/Atom feeds.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node connects to the specified feed urls in the input data table and parses information like title,
             description, publication date and article link from the feed entries. It is also possible to create a 
             Document and/or an XML column. The Document will be created from the feed entry information and the XML column 
             shows the XML snippet for the specific feed entry.
             
            The RSS Feed Parser uses the <a href="https://rometools.github.io/rome/ROMEReleases/index.html">ROME(1.0)</a> library. 
            ROME supports following formats and versions:
            <ul>
                <li>RSS 2.0</li>
                <li>RSS 1.0</li>
                <li>RSS 0.94</li>
                <li>RSS 0.93</li>
                <li>RSS 0.92</li>
                <li>RSS 0.91 Userland</li>
                <li>RSS 0.91 Netscape</li>
                <li>RSS 0.90</li>
                <li>Atom 1.0</li>
                <li>RSS 0.3</li>
            </ul>
            For more information about <a href="https://rometools.github.io/rome/index.html">ROME</a>, visit their website.
        </intro>
        <option name="URL column">
            The urls to get the feeds from.
        </option>
        <option name="Number of threads">
            Select the number of threads.
        </option>
        <option name="Time out">
            Set the time (in ms) until the connection times out, when no connection could be established. It also sets the
            time for timing out, when a connection could be established but the reading of the url takes too long.
        </option>
        <option name="Create Document column">
            If checked, the node creates an additional Document column for each feed entry.
        </option>
        <option name="Create XML column">
            If checked, the node creates an additional XML column, containing the XML snippet for each feed entry.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>      
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Input table" index="0">
            An input table which contains a string column with urls to RSS or Atom feeds.
        </inPort>
        <outPort name="Output table" index="0">
            An output table which contains parsed feed information.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>