<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../../../../../../icons/TextProcFrequencies.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Frequency Filter</name>
	
	<shortDescription>
	   Filters terms with a specified frequency value.
	</shortDescription>
	
	<fullDescription>
	<intro>
        Filters terms in the given bag of words (input data table) and if
        specified in the documents as well, with a certain frequency value.
        On the one hand minimum and maximum values can be defined to be
        used for filtering. If the value of a specified frequency column
        is less than the minimum or greater than the maximum value the term is
        filtered. On the other hand a number k of terms to keep can be defined. 
        Only those k terms with the highest frequency value are kept, the rest 
        is filtered. 
	</intro>
        <option name="Deep filtering">
             If deep filtering is checked, the terms contained inside
             the documents are filtered too, this means that the documents are
             changed, which is more time consuming.
        </option>
        <option name="Document column">
              Specifies the column containing the documents to apply the 
              filtering.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Filter unmodifiable terms">
             Usually terms which have been set unmodifiable are not modified
             or filtered. If this setting is checked, these terms are filtered 
             as well if they don't fit the specified requirements.
        </option>
        <option name="Filter column">
             The column containing the values to apply the filtering, i.e.
             the TF measure of each term can be computed before by the TF node. 
             Once the column is appended, the filtering can be applied to this
             values.
        </option>
        <option name="Filter option">
             The filter option specifies which filtering is be applied, the
             Min-Max filtering or the K-Terms filtering. The Min-Max filtering
             keeps all rows with values contained in the specified filter column
             which are greater than the specified min and less than the maximum
             value. The K-Terms filter on the other hand keeps a number K
             rows with the highest values. 
        </option>
        <option name="Min-Max settings">
            Specifies the minimum and the maximum threshold of the values of
            the filter column.
        </option>
        <option name="Number settings">
            Specifies a number K of rows to keep, the rest is filtered out.
            Only these K rows with the highest value of the filter column are 
            kept.
        </option>        
	</fullDescription>
		
	<ports>
        <dataIn name="Terms and related documents input table" index="0">
        The input table which contains terms and documents.</dataIn>
        <dataOut name="Terms and documents output table" index="0">
        The output table which contains terms documents and a corresponding 
        frequency value.
        </dataOut>
	</ports>	
</knimeNode>

