<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcEnrichment.png" type="Learner">
    <name>StanfordNLP NE Learner</name>
    <shortDescription>
        Creates a StanfordNLP Named-Entity Model.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
			<p>
			The StanfordNLP NE Learner creates a conditional random field model based on documents and a dictionary
			with entities that occur in the documents. The chosen tag and the used dictionary will be saved internally, 
			so they can be used by the StanfordNLP NE tagger to tag new documents and validate the model.
			If you want to use the model externally, the model file can be found at your workflow directory:
			</p>
			<p><i>/%KNIMEWORKSPACE%/%WORKFLOW%/StanfordNLP NE Learner(##)/port_1/object/portobject.zip</i></p>
            <p>
            You can select the document column and the dictionary column to train your model with.
            It is possible to use multi-term entities within the dictionary.
            There is also a tab in the dialog to specify the learner properties.
            Currently, there are only a few options, since the number of
            parameters is pretty huge. So please contact us, if there are important/highly used parameters,
            we should integrate!
			</p>
			<p>
			<b>NOTE</b>: If you are interested in the StanfordNLP toolkit, please visit 
			<a href="http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/">http://nlp.stanford.edu/software/</a>.
			Some of the following property descriptions are taken from the
			<a href="http://nlp.stanford.edu/nlp/javadoc/javanlp/edu/stanford/nlp/ie/NERFeatureFactory.html">NERFeatureFactory</a>
			class from StanfordNLP. Please look into it for further information.
			</p>
        </intro> 
        <tab name="Learner options">
        <option name="Document column">
        	The document column to train the model with.
        </option>
        <option name="String column">
        	The string column containing the entities to train the model with.
        </option>
        <option name="Tag type">
        The tag type to train the model with. This information will be used, if you forward the model to the Stanford NLP NE tagger.
        </option>
        <option name="Tag value">
        	The tag value to train the model with. This information will be used, if you forward the model to the Stanford NLP NE tagger.
        </option>
        <option name="Word tokenizer">
            Select the tokenizer used for word tokenization. Go to <i>Preferences -> KNIME -> Textprocessing</i>
            to read the description for each tokenizer.
        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Learner Properties">
        <option name="maxLeft">
        	The maximum context of class features used.
        </option>
		<option name="Use Class Feature">
				Include a feature for the class (as a class marginal). Puts a prior on the classes which is equivalent to how often the feature appeared in the training data.
        </option>
        <option name="Use Word">
        		Gives you feature for word.
        </option>
        <option name="Use NGrams">
        	Make features from letter n-grams, i.e., substrings of the word.
        </option>
        <option name="No Mid NGrams">
        	Do not include character n-gram features for n-grams that contain neither the beginning or end of the word.
        </option>
        <option name="Max NGram Length">
        	If this number is positive, n-grams above this size will not be used in the model.
        </option>
        <option name="Use Prev">
        	Enables previous features.
        </option>
        <option name="Use Next">
        	Enables next features.
        </option>
        <option name="Use Disjunctive">
        	   Include in features giving disjunctions of words anywhere in the left or
        	   right disjunctionWidth words (preserving direction but not position).
        </option>
        <option name="Use Sequences">
        	Does not use any class combination features if this is false.
        </option>
		<option name="Use Prev Sequences">
        	Does not use any class combination features using previous classes if this is false.
        </option>
        <option name="Use Type Seqs">
        	Use basic zeroeth order word shape features.
        </option>
        <option name="Use Type Seqs2">
        	Add additional first and second order word shape features
        </option>
        <option name="Use Type YSeqs">
        	Some first order word shape patterns.
        </option>
        <option name="Word Shape">
        	Either "none" for no wordShape use, or the name of a word shape function
        </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
        
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Documents input table" index="0">The input table
        containing the documents to train the model with.</inPort>
        <inPort name="Dictionary input table" index="1">The input dictionary
        containing known single- and/or multi-term entities to train the model.</inPort>
        <outPort name="Model output" index="0">The StanfordNLP NE model.</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>