<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcDefault.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Stop Word Filter</name>
    <shortDescription>Filters document terms contained in the stop word list.</shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	Filters all terms of the input documents, which are contained in the specified stop word list and/or in the second input table.
        	The node provides built-in stop word lists for various languages. Additionally, stop words can be passed to
        	the second input port. At least one stopword list (built-in or custom list) has to be selected in the dialog.
		</intro>

        <tab name="Filter options">
        <option name="Use built-in list">
              Specifies if built-in stop word list is used or not. If checked
              the second input table will be ignored.
        </option>
        <option name="Stopword lists">
              Available built-in stop word lists. If "Use built-in list" is
              checked, the built-in stop word list to use can be specified here.
        </option>
        <option name="Use custom list">
              If checked, the custom stop word list from the second input port is used.
        </option>
        <option name="Stopword column">
              The string column from the second input port which contains one stop word per row.
        </option>
        <option name="Case sensitive">
              If checked the stop words are matched case sensitive otherwise not.
        </option>
        
        </tab>

        <tab name="Preprocessing options">
        <option name="Document column">
            The column containing the documents to preprocess.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Replace documents">
            If checked, the documents will be replaced by the new preprocessed documents. Otherwise the preprocessed
            documents will be appended as new column. 
        </option>

        <option name="Append column">
            The name of the new appended column, containing the preprocessed documents.            
        </option>
        
        <option name="Ignore unmodifiable tag">
              If checked, unmodifiable terms will be preprocessed too.
        </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort name="Documents to preprocess" index="0">
            The input table which contains the documents to preprocess.
        </inPort>
		<inPort name="Stop words" index="1">
            The input table which contains a string column with one stop word per row.
        </inPort>
        <outPort name="Preprocessed documents." index="0">
            The output table which contains the preprocessed documents.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>