<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcFrequencies.png" type="Learner">
    <name>NGram creator</name>
    <shortDescription>Creates ngrams of documents.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node creates ngrams from the documents of the input table
            and counts their frequencies. 
            It can be specified whether word or character ngrams are created.
            Furthermore it can be specified whether the output table is of a 
            bag of words like structure or a data table containing ngrams and
            their frequencies in the corpus and documents.     
        </intro>
        <option name="N">
            The N value for ngram creation.
        </option>
        <option name="NGram type">
            The type (Word or Character) specifies whether word or character
            ngrams are created. 
        </option>
        <option name="Document column">
            The column containing the input documents to create the ngrams of.
        </option>
        <option name="Output table">
            Specifies the structure of the output data table. The "Ngram 
            frequencies" option creates an output table consisting of all
            ngrams and their frequencies in the complete corpus, as well as
            the documents and sentences or words. 
            Please note that this option is memory consuming for a large number
            of documents.<br/>
            
            The "NGram bag of words"
            option creates an output data table consisting of ngram and
            document tuples. A tuple represents the occurrence of an ngram
            in a document. Additionally the frequency column contains the
            number of occurrences of the ngram in the document. This option
            can also be applied on a large set of documents.
        </option>
        <option name="Number of maximal parallel processes">
            Specifies the maximal number of parallel processes running for
            ngram computation.
        </option>
        <option name="Number of documents to process in one process">
            Specifies the number of documents to be processed by a single
            process.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
        
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Documents input table" index="0">The input table
        containing the documents.</inPort>    
        <outPort name="Ngrams" index="0">The output table
        containing the ngrams and their corresponding frequencies,
        or a bag of ngrams.</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>