<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Abner Filter</name>
    <shortDescription>Filters terms with biomedical named entity tags not 
    specified as valid.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Filters all terms contained in the given bag of words (input table) 
            that have biomedical named entity (BNER) tags assigned which are 
            not specified as valid. The terms are filtered out of the bag of 
            words and the documents as well if deep preprocessing is checked.
            <br />
            To detect biomedical named entities, the ABNER 
            (A Biomedical Named Entity Recognizer) Software is used
            (see http://pages.cs.wisc.edu/~bsettles/abner/ for details).
            <br />
            A term is kept if at least one of its assigned BNER tags is a valid 
            tag. If strict filtering is set, all assigned BNER tags of a term 
            have to be valid. 
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Strict filtering">
             If strict filtering is checked, all tags (of a certain type) of the
             term have to be valid. If setting is not checked, at least
             one tag has to be valid.
        </option>
        <option name="Tags">
             The tags to use as valid tags.
        </option>
        
        <option name="Document column">
              Specifies the column containing the documents to preprocess.
        </option>
        <option name="Deep preprocessing">
             If deep preprocessing is checked, the terms contained inside
             the documents are converted too, this means that the documents are
             changed, which is more time consuming. 
        </option>
        <option name="Append original document">
            If append original document is checked, the documents contained in
            the input document column are appended as extra column. This
            enables later on a mapping of preprocessed documents to original
            documents.  
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
        
    <ports>
        <dataIn name="Terms and related documents input table" index="0">
        The input table which contains the terms to filter.</dataIn>
        <dataOut name="Filtered terms and related documents output table" index="0">
        The output table which contains the filtered terms.
        </dataOut>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>