<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcVectors.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Document vector</name>
    <shortDescription>Creates a document vector for each document.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            This node creates a document vector for each document representing
            it in the terms space. The values of the feature vectors can be 
            specified as boolean values or as values of a specified column 
            i.e. an tf*idf column. The dimension of the vectors will be the
            number of distinct terms in the BoW.
        </intro>
        <option name="Document column">
             The column containing the documents to use.
        </option>
        <option name="Ignore tags">
             If checked tags are ignored when comparing terms.
        </option>
        <option name="Bitvector">
             If checked a bitvector will be created indicating whether a 
             certain term is contained in a document or not.
        </option>
        <option name="Vector value">
             If Bitvector setting is not checked it is possible to specify the
             column to use as feature vector values. The column can i.e. contain
             tf*idf values which are than used as values of the feature vector.
             Be aware that you have to compute these values before using this
             node. To do so i.e. the frequency calculation nodes can be used.
        </option>
        <option name="As collection cell">
             If checked all vector entries will be stored in a collection cell
             consisting of double cells. The cells are ordered, the ordering
             is specified in the data table spec. If not checked all double
             cells will be stored in corresponding columns. The advantage 
             of the column representation is that most of the regular algorithms
             in KNIME can be applied. The disadvantage is (which is on the 
             other hand the advantage of the collection representation) that
             processing of subsequent nodes will be slowed down, due to the many
             columns that will be created (dependent on the input data of 
             course).
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
        
    <ports>
        <inPort name="Documents input table" index="0">The input table
        containing the bag of words.</inPort>    
        <outPort name="Documents output table" index="0">An output table
        containing the documents with the related document vectors.</outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>