<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcSource.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Strings To Document</name>
    <shortDescription>Converts the specified strings to documents.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Converts the specified strings to documents. For each row a document
            will be created and attached to that row. The strings of the
            specified columns will be used as title, authors, and 
            full text. Furthermore the defined category, source, type, and
            date will be set.
        </intro>
        <option name="Title">
            The selection to define whether to set the content of a column, the row ids or empty strings as title.
        </option>
        <option name="Title column">
            The column containing the string which is used as title. (if "Use title from column" is checked, otherwise a default title will be generated).
        </option>
        <option name="Full text">
            The column containing the string which is used as text.
        </option>
        <option name="Document source">
            The source which is set to all documents (if 
            "Use sources from column" is not checked).
        </option>
        <option name="Use sources from column">
            If checked, the string values of the specified column will be used
            as document sources.
        </option>        
        <option name="Document source column">
            The column containing the string used as source. No source is set 
            for missing values.
        </option>
        <option name="Document category">
            The category which is set to all documents (if 
            "Use categories from column" is not checked).
        </option>
        <option name="Use categories from column">
            If checked, the string values of the specified column will be used
            as document categories.
        </option>        
        <option name="Document category column">
            The column containing the string used as category. No category is 
            set for missing values.
        </option>
        <option name="Use author(s) from column">
            If checked, the string values of the specified column will be used
            as author(s).
        </option>
        <option name="Authors column">
            The column containing the author's names as a string which is split by the separation string.
            The string contained in the specified columns should follow this pattern: 
            FirstName LastName, FirstName LastName, ... (comma as separation string)
            Second names will be appended to the first name.            
        </option>
        <option name="Author name separator">
            The string separating the author names contained in the authors column.
        </option>
        <option name="Default author first name">
            The default author first name if "use author(s) from column" is unchecked.
        </option>
                <option name="Default author last name">
            The default author last name if "use author(s) from column" is unchecked.
        </option>
        <option name="Document type">
            The type which is set to all documents.
        </option>
        <option name="Date">
            The publication date as which is set to all documents (if 
            "Use publication date from column" is not checked).
        </option>
        <option name="Use publication date from column">
            If checked, the date value of the specified column will be used as document publication date.
        </option>
        <option name="Publication date column">
            The column containing the date which is used as publication date. (if "Use publication date from column" 
            is checked, otherwise the current date from "Publication date" field is set as date). 
            Note: The column type must be Date only. To convert the date &amp; time type to date only,
            consider using "Modify time" node to remove time. If the column has the legacy date &amp; time type,
            consider using the node "Legacy Date&amp;Time To Date&amp;Time" for conversion.
        </option>
        <option name="Document column">
            Specify the name of the document column to be created.
        </option>
        <option name="Word tokenizer">
            Select the tokenizer used for word tokenization. Go to <i>Preferences -> KNIME -> Textprocessing</i>
            to read the description for each tokenizer.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort name="String input table" index="0">
        An input data table containing string cells.ht
        </inPort>
        <outPort name="String and document output table" index="0">
        An output table containing the strings of the data of the input table as
        well as the created documents in an additional column.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
