<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcSource.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Strings To Document</name>
    <shortDescription>Converts the specified strings to documents.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Converts the specified strings to documents. For each row a document
            will be created and attached to that row. The strings of the
            specified columns will be used as title, authors, and 
            full text. Furthermore the defined category, source, type, and
            date will be set.
        </intro>
        <option name="Use title from column">
            If checked, the string values of the specified column will be used
            as title.
        </option>
        <option name="Title">
            The column containing the string which is used as title. (if "Use title from column" is checked, otherwise a default title will be generated).
        </option>
        <option name="Use author(s) from column">
            If checked, the string values of the specified column will be used
            as author(s).
        </option>
        <option name="Authors">
            The column containing the string which is split up
            and used as author names. (if "Use authors from column" is checked, otherwise the values of the labels 
            "Default author first name" and "Default author last name" will be set as author names).
        </option>
        <option name="Author name separator">
            The string separating the author names.
        </option>
        <option name="Default author first name">
            The default author first name if author first name is missing.
        </option>
                <option name="Default author last name">
            The default author last name if author last name is missing.
        </option>
                <option name="Full text">
            The column containing the string which is used as text.
        </option>
        <option name="Document source">
            The source which is set to all documents (if 
            "Use sources from column" is not checked).
        </option>
        <option name="Use sources from column">
            If checked, the string values of the specified column will be used
            as document sources.
        </option>        
        <option name="Document source column">
            The column containing the string used as source. No source is set 
            for missing values.
        </option>
        <option name="Document category">
            The category which is set to all documents (if 
            "Use categories from column" is not checked).
        </option>
        <option name="Use categories from column">
            If checked, the string values of the specified column will be used
            as document categories.
        </option>        
        <option name="Document category column">
            The column containing the string used as category. No category is 
            set for missing values.
        </option>
        <option name="Document type">
            The type which is set to all documents.
        </option>
        <option name="Publication date">
            The publication date as which is set to all documents (if 
            "Use publication date from column" is not checked).
            The date has to be formatted like "dd-mm-yyy". Two digits
            to specify the day, two to specify the month and four to
            specify the year. The specified date has to be a valid date.
        </option>
        <option name="Use publication date from column">
            If checked, the string value of the specified column will be used as document publication date.
            This node also allows the Date columns as an input columns.
        </option>
        <option name="Publication date column">
            The column containing the string which is used as publication date. (if "Use publication date from column" 
            is checked, otherwise the current date from "Publication date" field is set as date). The date has to be
            formatted like "dd-mm-yyy".
        </option>
        <option name="Word tokenizer">
            Select the tokenizer used for word tokenization. Go to <i>Preferences -> KNIME -> Textprocessing</i>
            to read the description for each tokenizer.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
    <ports>
        <inPort name="String input table" index="0">
        An input data table containing string cells.ht
        </inPort>
        <outPort name="String and document output table" index="0">
        An output table containing the strings of the data of the input table as
        well as the created documents in an additional column.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
