<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Strings To Document</name>
    <shortDescription>Converts the specified strings to documents.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Converts the specified strings to documents. For each row a document
            will be created and attached to that row. The strings of the
            specified columns will be used as title, authors, and 
            full text. Furthermore the specified category, source type and
            date is set to the documents too
        </intro>
        
        <option name="Title">
            Specifies the column containing the string which is used as title.
        </option>
        <option name="Full text">
            Specifies the column containing the string which is used as text.
        </option>
        <option name="Authors">
            Specifies the column containing the string which is split up
            and used as author names.
        </option>
        <option name="Author name separator">
            Specifies the string separating the author names.
        </option>
        <option name="Document source">
            Specifies the source which is set to all documents.
        </option>
        <option name="Document category">
            Specifies the category which is set to all documents.
        </option>
        <option name="Document type">
            Specifies the type which is set to all documents.
        </option>
        <option name="Publication date">
            Specifies the publication as which is set to all documents.
            The date has to be formatted like "dd-mm-yyy". Two digits
            to specify the day, two to specify the month and four to
            specify the year. The specified date has to be a valid date.
        </option>
    </fullDescription>
        
    <ports>
        <dataIn name="String input table" index="0">
        An input data table containing string cells.
        </dataIn>
        <dataOut name="String and document output table" index="0">
        An output table containing the strings of the data of the input table as
        well as the created documents in an additional column.
        </dataOut>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
