<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcDefault.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>Stanford Lemmatizer</name>
	<shortDescription>Returns the lemma of document terms using the
		Stanford Core NLP library.</shortDescription>
	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			Lemmatizes terms contained in the input documents with the Stanford
			Core NLP library. For details about the	Stanford Core NLP library, please check
			<a href="http://stanfordnlp.github.io/CoreNLP/index.html">here</a>.
			<br />
			<br />
			This node returns the lemma of a term by removing inflections, e.g
			in case of plurals, pronoun case, and verb endings. The lemma is based
			heavily on the Part-Of-Speech (POS) tag of a term, so either the
			Stanford tagger node or the POS tagger node has to be applied before
			using the Lemmatizer. If more than one POS tag is found for one term,
			only the first one will be taken into consideration. Moreover, terms with no
			POS tag will be skipped by default.
			<br />
			<br />
			Currently only english language is supported by	this node.
		</intro>

		<tab name="Lemmatizer options">
			<option name="Skip terms with no POS tag">
				If checked, the node will fail when at least one term has no POS tag. Otherwise, all terms that have no
				POS tag will simply be skipped.
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="Preprocessing options">
			<option name="Document column">
				The column containing the documents to preprocess.
			</option>

			<option name="Replace column">
				If checked, the document column will be replaced by the new preprocessed documents. Otherwise the
				preprocessed documents will be appended as a new column.
			</option>

			<option name="Append column">
				The name of the new appended column, containing the preprocessed documents.
			</option>

			<option name="Ignore unmodifiable tag">
				If checked, unmodifiable terms will be preprocessed too.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort name="Documents to preprocess" index="0">
			The input table which contains the documents to preprocess.
		</inPort>
		<outPort name="Preprocessed documents." index="0">
			The output table which contains the preprocessed documents.
		</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>