<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcDefault.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Dict Replacer</name>
    <shortDescription>Replaces document terms that match with dictionary keys by the corresponding specified values.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Replaces terms contained in the input documents that match with specified dictionary terms
            by the corresponding specified value. The dictionary file need to be specified. Each line of the
             dictionary file must contain a key and a value. If the key matches with a term, the term is replaced by
            the value. The key and value pairs must be separated by ",".
		</intro>
        <tab name="Preprocessing options">
        <option name="Document column">
            The column containing the documents to preprocess.
        </option>
        <option name="Replace documents">
            If checked, the documents will be replaced by the new preprocessed documents. Otherwise the preprocessed
            documents will be appended as new column. 
        </option>
        <option name="Append column">
            The name of the new appended column, containing the preprocessed documents.            
        </option>
        <option name="Ignore unmodifiable tag">
            If checked, unmodifiable terms will be preprocessed too.
        </option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Dictionary options">
        <option name="Dictionary file">
              The path of the dictionary file to use.
        </option>
        <option name="Replace words not in the dictionary by">
              If checked, all words that are not available in the dictionary are replaced by the string entered in the 
              text field.<br/>
              <i>Note:</i> Entering an empty string or a string consisting solely of whitespaces leads to the removal of 
              all terms not contained in the dictionary.
        </option>
        <option name="Word tokenizer">
            Select the tokenizer used for word tokenization. Go to <i>Preferences -> KNIME -> Textprocessing</i>
            to read the description for each tokenizer.
        </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort name="Documents to preprocess" index="0">
            The input table which contains the documents to preprocess.
        </inPort>
        <outPort name="Preprocessed documents." index="0">
            The output table which contains the preprocessed documents.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>