<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../../icons/TextProcDefault.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Oscar Filter</name>
    <shortDescription>Filters terms with certain chemical named entity tags.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Filters all terms contained in the given bag of words (input table)
            with chemical named entities tags assigned,
            (not) specified in the dialog. The terms are filtered out of the bag of
            words and the documents as well if deep preprocessing is checked.
            <br />
            To detect chemical named entities, the OSCAR
            framework version 4.1.2 is used
            (see https://bitbucket.org/wwmm/oscar4/overview for details).
            <br />
            A term is kept if at least one of its assigned chemical tags is a valid
            tag. If strict filtering is set, all assigned chemical tags of a term
            have to be valid.
        </intro>

        <tab name="Preprocessing options">
        <option name="Strict filtering">
             If strict filtering is checked, terms need to have all specified
             tags applied. If  not checked, at least one tag has to be applied.
        </option>
        <option name="Filter matching">
             If checked, terms which have the specified tags are filtered,
             otherwise they are kept. If strict filtering is checked, all tags
             must match to filter or keep a term.
        </option>
        <option name="Tags">
             The tags to filter for.
        </option>
        </tab>

        <tab name="Deep preprocessing options">
        <option name="Deep preprocessing">
             If deep preprocessing is checked, the terms contained inside
             the documents are preprocessed too, this means that the documents
             themselves are changed too, which is more time consuming.
        </option>
        <option name="Document column">
              Specifies the column containing the documents to preprocess.
        </option>
        <option name="Append unchanged documents">
            If checked, the documents contained in the specified "Original
            Document column" are appended unchanged even if deep preprocessing
            is checked. This helps to keep the original documents in the
            output data table without the agonizing pain of joining.
        </option>
        <option name="Original Document column">
              Specifies the column containing the original documents which
              can be attached unchanged.
        </option>
        <option name="Ignore unmodifiable tag">
              If checked unmodifiable terms will be preprocessed too.
        </option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort name="Terms and related documents input table" index="0">
        The input table which contains the terms to filter.</inPort>
        <outPort name="Filtered terms and related documents output table" index="0">
        The output table which contains the filtered terms.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>