<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../../icons/TextProcDefault.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Dict Replacer (2 in ports)</name>
    <shortDescription>Replaces complete terms that match with dictionary keys by
    corresponding specified values.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Replaces complete terms that match with specified dictionary terms
            with a corresponding specified value. 
            
            The dictionary is provided by a additional data table at port 1, 
            consisting of at least two string columns. One string column 
            contains the strings to replace (keys) the other string column
            contains the replacement strings (values). The columns can be
            specified in the dialog. 
		</intro>

        <tab name="Dictionary">
        <option name="Column containing the strings to replace">
              The column containing the strings (words/terms) to replace (keys). 
        </option>
        <option name="Column containing the replacement strings">
              The column containing the replacement strings (values). 
        </option>
        </tab>

        <tab name="Deep preprocessing options">
        <option name="Deep preprocessing">
             If deep preprocessing is checked, the terms contained inside
             the documents are preprocessed too, this means that the documents
             themselves are changed too, which is more time consuming.
        </option>
        <option name="Document column">
              Specifies the column containing the documents to preprocess.
        </option>
        <option name="Append unchanged documents">
            If checked, the documents contained in the specified "Original
            Document column" are appended unchanged even if deep preprocessing
            is checked. This helps to keep the original documents in the
            output data table without the agonizing pain of joining.
        </option>
        <option name="Original Document column">
              Specifies the column containing the original documents which
              can be attached unchanged.
        </option>
        <option name="Ignore unmodifiable tag">
              If checked unmodifiable terms will be preprocessed too.
        </option>
        </tab>
	</fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort name="Terms and related documents input table" index="0">
        The input table which contains the terms to convert.</inPort>
        <inPort name="Dictionary" index="1">
        The input table containing at least of two string columns (dictionary).
        </inPort>
        <outPort name="Filtered terms and related documents output table" index="0">
        The output table which contains the preprocessed terms.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>