<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../../icons/TextProcDefault.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>Dict Replacer (2 In-Ports)</name>
    <shortDescription>Replaces complete document terms that match with dictionary keys by corresponding specified values.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
            Replaces complete terms contained in the input documents that match with specified dictionary terms
            with a corresponding specified value. 
            
            The dictionary is provided by a additional data table at the second data port, consisting of at least two
            string columns. One string column contains the strings to replace (keys) the other string column contains 
            the replacement strings (values). The columns can be specified in the dialog. 
		</intro>
        <tab name="Preprocessing options">
        <option name="Document column">
            The column containing the documents to preprocess.
        </option>
        <option name="Replace documents">
            If checked, the documents will be replaced by the new preprocessed documents. Otherwise the preprocessed
            documents will be appended as new column. 
        </option>
        <option name="Append column">
            The name of the new appended column, containing the preprocessed documents.            
        </option>
        <option name="Ignore unmodifiable tag">
              If checked, unmodifiable terms will be preprocessed too.
        </option> 
        </tab>
        <tab name="Dictionary">
        <option name="Column containing the strings to replace">
              The column containing the strings (words/terms) to replace (keys). 
        </option>
        <option name="Column containing the replacement strings">
              The column containing the replacement strings (values). 
        </option>
		<option name="Replace words not in the dictionary by">
              If checked, all words that are not available in the dictionary are replaced by the string entered in the 
              text field.
        </option>
        <option name="Word tokenizer">
            Select the tokenizer used for word tokenization. Go to <i>Preferences -> KNIME -> Textprocessing</i>
            to read the description for each tokenizer.
        </option>  
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>

    <ports>
        <inPort name="Documents to preprocess" index="0">
            The input table which contains the documents to preprocess.
        </inPort>
        <inPort name="Dictionary" index="1">
            The input table containing at least of two string columns (dictionary).
        </inPort>        
        <outPort name="Preprocessed documents." index="0">
            The output table which contains the preprocessed documents.
        </outPort>
    </ports>
</knimeNode>