<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="../../../icons/TextProcDoc2String.png" type="Manipulator" deprecated="true">
    <name>Meta Info Extractor</name>
    <shortDescription>Extracts the meta info key, value pairs of documents.
    </shortDescription>
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
			Extracts the meta information key, value pairs of documents. It can be specified whether the documents
			are appended or not and if duplicate documents in the input table are ignored and meta information is
			extracted only for distinct documents. Furthermore keys can be specified for which the key value pairs
			are extracted. Since there may be several key, value pair for each document original row ids can not be
			kept. For each key, value pair of a document a row in the output table exists. The output table contains
			at least two columns, one with the keys and another with the values. A third column containing the documents
			itself is appended if specified in the dialog. 
			
			Documents that are missing or that do not contain selected keys, or any keys at all will be omitted.
		</intro>
		<option name="Document column">The document column to use.</option>
		<option name="Append documents">If checked a column containing the documents is appended.</option>
		<option name="For distinct documents only">If checked duplicate documents are ignored.</option>
		<option name="Extract only meta info for specified keys">If checked only meta infos for specified keys are 
        extracted. Otherwise all key value pairs will be extracted.</option>
		<option name="Meta info keys (comma separated)">The keys of the meta infos to extract. Multiple keys must be 
        comma separated.</option>
	</fullDescription>
		
	<ports>
        <inPort name="Documents input table" index="0">
        The input table which contains the documents.</inPort>
        <outPort name="Documents and extracted meta info." index="0">
        The output table which contains documents and the extracted meta information.</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>